National Arts Club
Archives of American Art, Smithsonian Institution
Wild West party planned to benefit Jr. Members Scholarship Fund; to close 40th anniversary celebration. New York Times II, 2:8, April 23; New York Times II, 3:1, April 30.
Jr. Members plan New Year's Eve Olympian Ball. New York Times 30:2, December 19; New York Times II, 1:2, December 31.
1940
Art by deceased life members to be sold. New York Times 17:2, January 5.
Group show; awards. New York Times 21:2, January 11.
Group show. New York Times 24:2, January 24; New York Times IX, 9:2, January 28.
Non-members exhibition. Art News 38:15, February 3.
Exhibits: ceramics. New York Times 17:4, February 16; Ceramics and flowers. New York Times 15:5, February 19; Ceramics. New York Times II, 5:2, February 25; Exhibits: Jr. members. New York Times IX, 10:2, April 14; Group show awards. New York Times 21: 5, April 25.
Pan-American Ball held. New York Times 21:5, April 20.
Fund campaign for refugee artists started. New York Times 8:2, July 31.
Establishes artist refugee fund. New York Times 19:1, August 1.
Benefit exhibit plans. New York Times 20:8, October 2; Exhibit. New York Times IX, 5:4, October 6.
County fair planned. New York Times II, 3:3, October 6.
Refugee artists show their work. Art News 39:10, October 12.
Annual book exhibit opens. New York Times 3:5, November 3.
Testimonial luncheon for foreign authors in U.S. New York Times 45:2, November 10.
National Arts Club dramatizes books at the 35th annual new books of the year exhibition. Publishers Weekly 138:2046, November 30.
1941
Annual members' exhibit. New York Times 24:8, January 10; Comment. New York Times IX, 9:2, January 12; Awards. New York Times 24:6, January 23.
Annual prizes. Art Digest 15:13, February 1.
Benefits concerts planned. New York Times 39:1, February 23; New York Times 20:7, March 28.
Annual exhibit awards. New York Times 28:3, March 11; Comment. New York Times I, 10:3, March 16.
Group shows. New York Times IX, 10:1, March 30; New York Times IX, 8:2, May 25; New York Times X, 13:5, May 25; New York Times IX, 7:5, June 15.
Book exhibit. New York Times 1:6,November 9.
1942
Group show. New York Times X, 10:1, January 18.
Group show. New York Times 14:4, February 4; Private preview. New York Times 15:4, February 5; Comment. New York Times IX, 9:6, February 8.
Jr. members to honor servicemen at Hallowe'en party. New York Times 16:3, October 30.
37th annual show of new books. Publishers Weekly 142:2044, November 14.
To sponsor Chinese and Indian art exhibit in NYC. New York Times VIII, 9:1, December 13; Exhibit. New York Times 42:5, December 17.
1945
Holds Xmas fair. New York Times 13:3, November 16.
1946
Contemporary American painting exhibit planned. New York Times 23:6, February 20.
Jr. members and young non-members exhibition. Art News 45:67, May.
Annual book show plans. New York Times 21:2, November 1; Show, W.L. Laurence speaks. New York Times 13:1, November 12.
Annual book show. Publishers Weekly 150:2731, 2718, November 9.
Packaging the book. P. Boswell. Art Digest 21:3, November 15.
Choosing best book jackets, 41st annual book show. Art News 45:8, December.
1947
Preview exhibit. New York Times 21:5, January 9.
Forming symphony orchestra. New York Times 27:1, September 19.
1948
Ninth annual exhibition of American Veterans Society of Artists. Art Digest 22:19, January 1.
Conservatives score at the 50th annual exhibition of painting and sculpture. Art Digest 22:17, February 1.
Fiftieth annual exhibition. Art News 47:49, March.
Book fair opens in NYC. New York Times 30:7, December 9.
1949
Summer annual. Art Digest 23:14, August.
Dinner honors Mrs. F.D. Roosevelt. New York Times 39:5, October 11.
1950
Fifty-second annual exhibition of oils and sculptures. Art Digest 24:12, January 15.
Members' summer exhibition. Art Digest 24:18, August.
Fair plans. New York Times 44:8, November 1.
1951
Members-guests annual. New York Times II, 19:1, January 14.
53rd Annual Exhibition. Art Digest 25:18, January 15; Art News 49:47, February.
Non-members annual. New York Times 21:5, March 30.
Open competition for non-members. Art Digest 25:18, April 15.
Summer painting exhibition series opens. New York Times 42:8, June 7.
Members work. New York Times II, 6:4, June 17.
Summer exhibition. Art Digest 25:19, July.
1952
Fifty-fourth annual exhibition. Art Digest 26:19, January 15; Art News 49:47, February.
Members and guests annual. New York Times 59:2, January 6; Awards. New York Times 16:2, January 17.
Watercolor annual; awards. New York Times 14:4, February 8; Art News 51:56, March.
Non-members painting annual; awards. New York Times 16:5, March 10; New York Times 27:3, March 13.
Small pictures by members; awards. New York Times 25:5, April 9.
Exhibition of small oils. Art Digest 26:18-19, April 15; Art News 49:47, February.
1953
Theatre in an art gallery. A. Scheff. Theatre Arts 37:92, January.
Members-guests annual; awards. New York Times II, 11:2, January 11.
Non-members painting annual; awards. New York Times 21:5., February 19.
Members work; awards. New York Times II, 13:2, May 10; New York Times II, 8:5, June 21.
1954
Painting and sculpture annual by members and guests. New York Times 25:5, January 26.
Fifty-sixth annual exhibition. Arts Digest 28:17, February 1.
Members and non-members annual; contemporary watercolors; awards. New York Times 27:5, February 11; Review. New York Times II, 14:2, February 14.
Grand national annual members' competition. Art News 53:63, May.
1955
Painting and sculpture annual; awards. New York Times 23:1, January 12.
Fifty-sixth annual exhibition. Arts Digest 28:17, February 1.
Paintings annual; awards. New York Times 18:4, March 1.
Annual exhibition of American oil paintings. Art Digest 29:26, March 15.
Poet P. MacKaye honored on 80th birthday. New York Times 28:2, March 16.
1957
Arts Club honors Neuman; WNYC. C. Durgin. Musical America 77:12, April.
Art Clubs of America. Artist 53:67, June.
1958
At founding [sixtieth anniversary]. New York Times 49:2, November 27.
First annual metropolitan young artists show; awards. New York Times 49:2, November 27
1959
Stadium Concerts founder Mrs. C.S. Guggenheimer gets scroll from Mayor Wagner and National Arts Club medal. New York Times 9:2, March 12.
1960
Tenor competition awards. New York Times 47:8, November 15.
Index Terms
This collection is indexed in the online catalog of the Archives of American Art under the following terms:
Subjects:
De Kay, Charles
Subjects-Topical:
Art -- Societies, etc.; Associations, institutions, etc. -- Taxation; Bibliographical exhibitions -- New York (State) -- New York; Clubhouses -- New York (State) -- New York; Decorative arts -- New York (State) -- New York -- Exhibitions; Handicraft -- New York (State) -- New York -- Exhibitions; Photography -- Exhibitions
Types of Materials:
Photograph albums; Photographs; Scrapbooks
Names:
Arts Realty
Provenance
The National Arts Club donated its records to the Archives of American Art in 1987. Although a limited amount of printed matter was available at various libraries and on microfilm through the Archives of American Art, scholars have not had access to unpublished records of the Club until this time.
Restrictions on Access
The collection is open for research. Patrons must use microfilm copy.
Alternative Forms Available
The bulk of the collection is available on microfilm reels 4237-4269. The microfilm is available for interlibrary loan.
Series Descriptions/Container Listing
- Board of Governors, 1898-1960, undated, Series 1:
  This series contains minutes and reports of the Board of Governors and Executive Committee from 1898 to 1957, and minutes and reports of various standing and special committees from 1901 to 1939. Board of Governors and Executive Committee minutes and reports are fairly complete through 1949, but sparse thereafter, and include transcriptions of very early correspondence relating to the selection and acquisition of the first clubhouse. Records for special committees are not complete either, and tend to be concentrated in the early twentieth century.
  The series is arranged by committee and then chronologically.
  - Board of Governors and Executive Committee (Reel 4237)
    - Volume 1, March 1, 1898-April 1905 (Reel 4237, Frame 6-516)
      (including records of the Organizing Secretary, Charles de Kay, and the Organizing Committee, with copies of the charter, constitution, and house rules)
    - Volume 2, May 1905-Oct. 1908 (Reel 4237, Frame 517-668)
    - Volume 3, June 1909-June 1910 (Reel 4237, Frame 669-715)
    - Volume 4 (regarding reorganization), April 12-June 29, 1910 (Reel 4237, Frame 716-745)
    - Volume 5, April 1910-April 1912 (Reel 4237, Frame 746-893)
    - Volume 6, April 1912-April 1913 (Reel 4237, Frame 894-979)
    - Volume 7, April 1913-April 1914 (Reel 4237, Frame 980-1071)
    - Volume 8, April 1914-March 1915 (Reel 4237, Frame 1072-1219)
    - Volume 9, April 1914-April 1915 (Reel 4237, Frame 1220-1235)
    - Volume 9, April 1914-April 1915 cont. (Reel 4238, Frame 8-101)
    - Volume 10, April 1918-April 1919 (Reel 4238, Frame 102-244)
    - Volume 11, April 1919-April 1920 (Reel 4238, Frame 245-378)
    - Volume 12, April 1920-April 1921 (Reel 4238, Frame 379-475)
    - Volume 13, April 1921-April 1922 (Reel 4238, Frame 476-596)
    - Volume 14, April 1922-April 1923 (Reel 4238, Frame 597-709)
    - Volume 15, April 1923-April 1924 (Reel 4238, Frame 710-800)
    - Volume 16, April 1924-April 1925 (Reel 4238, Frame 801-904)
    - Volume 17, April 1925-April 1926 (Reel 4238, Frame 905-990)
    - Volume 18, April 1926-April 1927 (Reel 4238, Frame 991-1095)
    - Volume 19, April 1927-April 1928 (Reel 4238, Frame 1096-1177)
    - Miscellaneous loose items, May-Dec. 1928 (Reel 4238, Frame 1178-1199)
    - Volume 20, April 1929-April 1930 (Reel 4238, Frame 1200-1275)
    - Volume 21, April 1930-April 1931 (Reel 4238, Frame 1276-1373)
    - Volume 22, April 1931-April 1932 (Reel 4238, Frame 1374-1439)
    - Volume 22, April 1931-April 1932, cont. (Reel 4239, Frame 1-97)
    - Volume 23, April 1932-April 1933 (Reel 4239, Frame 98-249)
    - Volume 24, April 1933-April 1934 (Reel 4239, Frame 250-354)
    - Volume 25, April 1934-April 1935 (Reel 4239, Frame 355-446)
    - Volume 26, April 1935-April 1936 (Reel 4239, Frame 447-543)
    - Volume 27, April 1936-April 1937 (Reel 4239, Frame 544-617)
    - Volume 28, April 1937-April 1938 (Reel 4239, Frame 617-690)
    - Volume 29, April 1938-Dec. 1942 (Reel 4239, Frame 691-967)
    - Volume 30, Jan. 1943-Aug. 1943 (Reel 4239, Frame 968-986)
    - Disbound volumes and loose minutes, 1943-1960 (Reel 4239, Frame 987-1417)
    - Disbound volumes and loose minutes, 1943-1960 cont. (Reel 4240, Frame 6-86)
  - Admissions Committee (Reel 4240)
    - Volume 1, Minutes, April 1901-May 1910 (Reel 4240, Frame 90-219)
    - Volume 2, Minutes, June 1910-Dec. 1918 (Reel 4240, Frame 220-379)
  - Arts Committee (Reel 4240)
    - Volume 1, Minutes, Oct. 1910-April 1919 (Reel 4240, Frame 381-495)
    - Volume 2, Minutes and report, Feb. 1939 (Reel 4240, Frame 496-595)
  - Decorative Arts Exhibition Committee (Reel 4240)
    - Minutes, 1929 (Reel 4240, Frame 596-604)
  - Extension Committee (Reel 4240)
    - Report, 1908 (Reel 4240, Frame 605-612)
  - General Committee on Financial Condition (Reel 4240)
    - Report, 1922 (Reel 4240, Frame 614-615)
  - House Committee (Reel 4240)
    - Volume 1, Minutes, April 1904-Sept. 1906 (Reel 4240, Frame 617-730)
    - Volume 2, Minutes, Aug. 1906-Sept. 1907 (Reel 4240, Frame 731-813)
    - Volume 3, Minutes and report, April 1919-July 1921, 1939 (Reel 4240, Frame 814-921)
  - Committee on Increased Membership (Reel 4240)
    - Report, undated (Reel 4240, Frame 922-924)
  - Committee on Membership (Reel 4240)
    - Consultant's Report, undated (Reel 4240, Frame 925-948)
  - Special Committee of Second Mortgage Bondholders (Reel 4240)
    - Minutes and Reports, 1910, 1915 (Reel 4240, Frame 949-975)
  - Special Committee on Restaurant (Reel 4240)
    - Reports, 1909 (Reel 4240, Frame 58-961)
- Administration, 1898-1960, undated, Series 2:
  This series contains correspondence of club officers and tends to be routine and administrative, relating particularly to the management of the restaurant and studio building, election of members, and collection of dues. Individual letters concerning important events in the history of the National Arts Club, or relating to art, artists, and the Club's permanent collection are noted in the subseries descriptions.
  This record series is comprised of eight subseries:
  2.1: Officers' Correspondence, 1898-1960, undated
  2.2: President, 1920, 1928
  2.3: Secretary, 1927-1939
  2.4: Treasurer, 1917-1957, undated
  2.5: Manager, 1956-1960
  2.6: House Committee, 1922-1932
  2.7: American Artists War Emergency Fund Committee, 1917-1918
  2.8: Men's Open Table, 1915-1950
  Due to coinciding responsibilities of officers and a number of efforts to organize the records over the years, there is overlap between Officers' Correspondence (especially General Correspondence) and other subseries. Wherever possible and practical, the arrangement reflects what appears to be the filing system used, at some point, by the Club.
  - Officers' Correspondence, 1898-1960, undated, 2.1:
    The Officers' Correspondence subseries includes several categories: General correspondence (organized chronologically), and subject files on mortgage bonds, exhibitions, studio building, and insurance. Officers represented are mainly the Secretary, Assistant Secretary, and President, but there is also correspondence of others including the Board of Governors, chairmen of various committees, and the Treasurer.
    Records relating to exhibitions typically include correspondence, sales, consignment and other accounting records, shipping receipts, catalog dummies and galley proofs, and miscellaneous publicity material.
    - undated (Reel 4240, Frame 976-1020)
    - 1898 (Reel 4240, Frame 1021-1062)
      (opinions of Charles L. Freer, Charles Henry Hart, Augustus Saint-Gaudens, Alfred Stieglitz, Stanford White, and others, offered in response to a circular describing the proposed National Arts Club)
    - 1898, cont. (Reel 4241, Frame 6-58)
    - 1899 (Reel 4241)
      William T. Evans on the inception of his collection
    - 1900 [Oct.-Dec. precedes Apr.-Sept.] (Reel 4241, Frame 131-263)
      (Charles Volkmar on decorative arts and gift of vases to NAC, report of Frederick Law Olmsted on site chosen for the Tome Institute, Port Deposit, Md., printed circular of NAC on decoration of the National Capitol with text of a bill to create a Capitol Art Commission, and Louis Agassiz Fuertes's letter about his exhibition with a list of pieces to be shown)
    - 1901 (Reel 4241, Frame 264-333)
      (Pan American Pacific Exposition instructions for exhibitors)
    - 1902 (Reel 4241, Frame 334-350)
    - 1903 (Reel 4241, Frame 351-364)
      (John Q. A. Ward on changes in management of NAC, and Bancel La Farge on proper lighting for exhibition of stained glass windows)
    - 1904 (Reel 4241, Frame 365-404)
      (American Institute of Architects protest against proposed Dept. of Agriculture buildings that would interfere with L'Enfant plan for D.C., with map)
    - 1905 (Reel 4241, Frame 405-430)
    - 1906 (Reel 4241, Frame 431-440)
    - 1907 (Reel 4241, Frame 441-460)
    - 1908 (Reel 4241, Frame 461-479)
    - 1909 (Reel 4241, Frame 480-524)
      (John de Witt Warner on the role of women in the National Arts Club)
    - 1910 (Reel 4241, Frame 525-553)
      (lists of important papers in the custody of the Club Secretary)
    - 1911 (Reel 4241, Frame 554-556)
    - 1912 (Reel 4241, Frame 557-560)
    - 1913 (Reel 4241, Frame 561-582)
      (petition requesting life membership to honor Frederick S. Lamb)
    - 1914 (Reel 4241, Frame 583-586)
    - 1915 (Reel 4241, Frame >587-597)
      (correspondence concerning competition for best critical manuscript on the Altman Collection)
    - 1916 (Reel 4241, Frame 598-606)
    - 1917 (Reel 4241, Frame 607-615)
    - 1918 (Reel 4241, Frame 616-909)
      (petition and correspondence concerning controversy involving Club Treasurer Alexander Konta, with transcript of "Cross Examination of Mr. Alexander Konta on Brewing and Liquor Interest and German Propaganda, Hearings before a Sub-Committee on the Judiciary, U.S. Senate)
    - 1919 (Reel 4241, Frame 910-983)
      (brochure about Co-Operative Art Building)
    - 1920 (Reel 4241, Frame 984-1013)
    - 1921 (Reel 4241, Frame 1014-1018)
    - 1922 (Reel 4241, Frame 1019-1022)
    - 1924 (Reel 4241, Frame 1023-1068)
      (form letter from John Quinn requesting NAC support in his fight to remove tax on art sales)
    - 1925 (Reel 4241, Frame 1069-1075)
    - 1927 (Reel 4241, Frame 1076-1106)
      (additional documents concerning Alexander Konta, and legal papers regarding objection of NAC to zoning changes proposed for neighboring property)
    - 1929 (Reel 4241, Frame 1107-1120)
    - 1930-1931 (Reel 4242, Frame 6-1072)
      ("Soul of America" contest sponsored by NAC)
    - 1933 (Reel 4242, Frame 1073)
    - 1934 (Reel 4242, Frame 1074)
    - 1935 (Reel 4242, Frame 1075-1163)
      (reminiscences of NAC's early years solicited from long-time members, including replies from J. William Fosdick, Dr. William Bainbridge, Thomas G. Taaffe, George P. Peabody, and Charles Vezin)
    - 1937 (Reel 4242, Frame 1164-1166)
    - 1938 (Reel 4242, Frame 1167-1228)
      (George Chapellier's notes on restoration of paintings exhibited at NAC)
    - 1939 (Reel 4242, Frame 1229-1395)
      (suggestion of J. Frederick Talcott to sell works by artist life members in order to raise money)
    - 1940 (Reel 4242, Frame 1396-1434)
      (correspondence with Helen Hayes concerning election to life membership)
    - 1941 (Reel 4243, Frame 6-323)
    - 1942 (Reel 4243, Frame 324-337)
    - 1943 (Reel 4243, Frame 338-359)
    - 1944 (Reel 4243, Frame 360-369)
    - 1945 (Reel 4243, Frame 369-373)
    - 1947 (Reel 4243, Frame 374)
    - 1948 (Reel 4243, Frame 375)
    - 1953 (Reel 4243, Frame 376-385)
    - 1954 (Reel 4243, Frame 386-408)
      (proposed amendments to constitution, and extensive suggestions of Walter Zahn for improved administration)
    - 1956 (Reel 4243, Frame 409-412)
    - 1957 (Reel 4243, Frame 413-438)
      (revision of constitution)
    - 1958 (Reel 4243, Frame 439-440)
    - 1959 (Reel 4243, Frame 441-455)
    - 1960 (Reel 4243, Frame 456-464)
      (amendments to Certificate of Incorporation, and establishment of Gregg Memorial Room)
  - War Tax Refund (see also Series 2: Administration, Treasurer) (Reel 4243)
    - Application and Supporting Documentation, 1922 (Reel 4243, Frame 467-816)
    - Correspondence with Treasury Department, Internal Revenue, and Attorneys, 1919-1922 (Reel 4243, Frame 817-941)
    - Correspondence with Organizations Requesting Information, 1922-1924 (Reel 4243, Frame 942-963)
    - Sample Form Letters to Members, 1922 (Reel 4243, Frame 964-967)
    - Correspondence with Members, 1922-1923 (Reel 4243, Frame 968-1384)
    - Correspondence with Members, 1922-1923, cont. (Reel 4244, Frame 6-266)
  - Mortgage Bonds (see also Series 1: Board of Governors, Special Committee of Second Mortgage Gondholder) (Reel 4244)
    - Memorandum summarizing background of First and Second Mortgage Bonds, undated (Reel 4244, Frame 268-276)
  - Arts Realty Co. (Reel 4244)
    - First Mortgage Bond - Subscriber Lists, 1906-1907, 1918 (Reel 4244, Frame 277-281)
    - First Mortgage Bond - Correspondence, 1918-1919, 1927-1928 (Reel 4244, Frame 282-789)
    - First Mortgage Bondholders' Coupons Paid (1 volume - only sample page microfilmed), 1919-1928 (Reel 4244, Frame 790-792)
    - Second Mortgage Bond - Subscriber Lists, 1906-1929, undated (Reel 4244, Frame 793-856)
    - Participation Trust Agreement concerning Second Mortgage Bond, 1918 (Reel 4244, Frame 857-886)
    - Second Mortgage Bond Certificate photostats, 1918 (Reel 4244, Frame 887-890)
    - Transfers, Assignments, and Miscellaneous Legal Documents concerning Second Mortgage Bond, 1911-1922, undated (Reel 4244, Frame 891-960)
    - Second Mortgage Bond - Correspondence, 1910-1930 (Reel 4244, Frame 961-1281)
    - Second Mortgage Bondholders' Coupons Paid (only sample page microfilmed), 1907-1926 (Reel 4244, Frame 1282-1284)
  - Exhibitions (Reel 4244)
    - Decorative Arts Exhibition, 1928 (Reel 4244, Frame 1287-1340)
    - Decorative Arts Exhibition, 1928, cont. (Reel 4245, Frame 5-558)
    - Books of the Year Exhibition, 1928 (Reel 4245, Frame 561-1053)
    - Decorative Arts Exhibition, 1929 (Reel 4245, Frame 1054-1361)
      (correspondence, sales and consignment records)
    - Decorative Arts Exhibition, 1929 (Reel 4245, Frame 4-636)
      (shipping receipts, mailing lists, publicity, and a book of entry blanks and receipts)
    - Decorative Arts Exhibition, 1929, cont. (Reel 4246, Frame 4-636)
    - Sixth Annual Exhibition of Living American Etchers, 1929 (Reel 4246, Frame 638-1186)
    - Decorative Arts Exhibition, 1930 (Reel 4246, Frame 1187-1205)
    - Twenty-Fifth Anniversary Exhibition of Books of the Year, 1930 (Reel 4246, Frame 1206-1214)
      (list of participating publishers)
    - Seventh Annual Exhibition of Living American Etchers (target incorrectly reads Decorative Arts Exhibition), 1930 (Reel 4246, Frame 1215-1378)
    - Seventh Annual Exhibition of Living American Etchers, 1930, cont. (Reel 4247, Frame 4-152)
    - Books of the Year Exhibition, 1946 (Reel 4247, Frame 153-918)
    - Books of the Year Exhibition, 1947 (Reel 4247, Frame 919-1393)
    - Books of the Year Exhibition, 1947, cont. (Reel 4248, Frame 4-443)
    - Books of the Year Exhibition, 1948 (Reel 4248, Frame 444-1374)
    - Books of the Year Exhibition, 1948, cont. (Reel 4249, Frame 4-178)
    - Books of the Year Exhibition, 1949 (Reel 4249, Frame 179-1169)
    - Books of the Year Exhibition, 1950 (Reel 4249, Frame 1170-1315)
    - Books of the Year Exhibition, 1950, cont. (Reel 4250, Frame 6-146)
    - Fiftieth Anniversary Exhibition of Books of the Year, 1956 (Reel 4250, Frame 148-214)
    - Books of the Year Exhibition, 1957 (Reel 4250, Frame 215-217)
    - International Exhibition of Painting and Sculpture (target omitted), 1957 (Reel 4250, Frame 218-312)
  - Studio Building (Reel 4250)
    - Lists of Applicants, Tenants, etc. (Reel 4250, Frame 317-342)
    - Correspondence, A-Z, 1920-1932 (Reel 4250, Frame 343-1073)
    - Leases and Related Legal Papers, 1923-1929 (Reel 4250, Frame 1074-1124)
  - Insurance (Reel 4250)
    - Appraisal and Inventory including art collection, 1920, 1954 (Reel 4250, Frame 1129-1169)
    - Policies and Related Correspondence (for building and contents, including fine arts) (Reel Unfilmed)
    - Unidentified Policies, and Correspondence Regarding More than One Category of Insurance (Reel Unfilmed)
  - President, 1920, 1928, 2.2:
    Correspondence found here concerns general Club business and the activities of various standing committees. Also included is printed matter issued by NAC and other arts organizations.
    - Correspondence, Jan.-May 1920, 1928 (Reel 4250, Frame 1172-1372)
    - Jan.-May 1920, 1928, cont. (Reel 4251, Frame 4-314)
  - Secretary, 1927-1939, 2.3:
    Correspondence in this subseries concerns resignations.
    - Correspondence, A-Z, 1927-1932 (Reel 4251, Frame 318-1401)
    - Correspondence, A-Z, 1927-1932, cont. (Reel 4252, Frame 4-24)
    - Correspondence, A-Z, 1933-1939 (Reel 4252, Frame 25-1445)
    - Correspondence, A-Z, 1933-1939, cont. (Reel 4253, Frame 4-42)
  - President, 1917-1957, undated, 2.4:
    This subseries begins with Tresurer's notebooks which contain correspondence, reports, and annotated copies of Board of Executive Committee minutes. Working papers include comparative statistics, balance sheets and printed Treasurer's reports, in addition to correspondence.